Maria Kustova

Software Engineer

Phone: +7 (904) 550-06-85 E-mail: maria.k@catit.be

Residence: St. Petersburg, Russia

Summary

Quality assurance engineer experienced in testing of various types of software including embedded systems and web-applications with skills in testing automation.

Technical Background

Programming languages: Python, JavaScript, Bash/Posix Shell, C OS: Linux, Windows, Mac OS

Experience

01.2013 - present Senior QA specialist - Luxoft

Smart TV platforms

Perform functional and certification testing of embedded Linux OS and middleware layer

Environment: Python, JavaScript, HTML, Bash/Posix Shell, DekTec and other streaming software, svn, JIRA

- developed and maintained the test framework consuming asynchronous calls to the middleware APIs and allowing to automate certification, functional and regression tests;
- developed tools for communication with scrambling modules via telnet;
- deployed and maintained the test lab including streaming, web-content and DLNA servers;
- designed test documentation: test plans, test scenarios for automation, test scenarios based on certification requirements;
- manual functional, smoke and certification testing.

YouTube Leanback for smart TVs

Provide various types of testing during the pre-certification phase

Environment: JavaScript, HTML, Bash/Posix Shell, svn, JIRA

- deployed and maintained the test lab for traffic shaping and hosting of the test web-content;
- designed test documentation: test plans, test scenarios based on certification requirements;
- manual and automation functional, performance, usability, regression and pre-certification testing.

01.2010 - 05.2011 Senior QA engineer — Kaspersky Lab

Antivirus products for Mac OS X

Perform functions of a team-lead and release QA engineer

Environment: Bash/Posix Shell, HP Quality Center

- implemented scripts for testing of CLI;
- performed review of product specifications and requirements;
- designed test documentation: test plans and test scenarios;
- performed manual functional, usability, regression, documentation and localization testing;
 processed customer feedback;
- organized work of a small team;
- was responsible for the quallity of testing process.

06.2007 - 10.2007 QA engineer — MetaCommunications Inc.

ERM/ERP system for publishing companies

Perform functional testing of web-based front-end

Environment: shell scripts, Borland Caliber, Virtual Ticket, perforce

- performed review of product specifications and requirements;
 designed test documentation: test plans and test scenarios for manual and automated testing;
- performed manual functional and usability testing.

11.2005 - 02.2007 **QA engineer — Amust/Veeam**

Enterprise client-server and consumer desktop applications

Perform manual testing of various types

Environment: VMware vCenter, VMware ESX

- designed test documentation: test plans and test scenarios for manual testing;
- performed manual functional, usability and stress testing.

Education

St. Petersburg University of Film and Television, Image processing, Specialist degree (1999 — 2004) St. Petersburg Academic University, Software engineering, Extern (2011 — 2012)

Languages

 ${\it Russian-native}.$

English — upper-intermediate.